残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽根があること
残酷な天使の定世 窓辺からやがて到達
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
ママ!
ママ! They chose me!
I'm an elite pilot now!
I'm the best in the whole world now!
I must keep this a secret, but I'll only tell you,ママ!
Everybody's so nice to me now!
I don't feel lonely anymore!
I'm okay now!
Even without Papa!
Look at me!
Look at me,ママ!
Look,ママ!
Sing ratio zero
I can't be the second child anymore
No reason left to live
Nobody cares about me anymore
My father, my mother, nobody cares
I have no reason left to live
Are you Oscar Langley, so are you?
Intelligence Division 2 just took the second child into protective custody
Right
It isn't like them to lose her in the first place
And then it takes seven days to find her
They must have done it on purpose
They're trying to make trouble for us, aren't they major?
It could be
And the fifth child arrives to replace Oscar today
This whole thing is just too convenient
Eya Nami
There's a feeling about her
Almost as if my mother
Rei and my mother
What are you doing with them?
Father
Hello, Commander
Did you know my cat died?
The cat my grandmother was taking care of
I hadn't seen it for a long time
But now I know that I'll never see it again
Why did you destroy the dummy system?
The cat my grandmother was taking care of
I hadn't seen it for a long time
But now I know that I'll never see it again
Why did you destroy the dummy system?
It wasn't the dummy system that I destroyed
It was Ray
I'll ask you once more
Why did you do it?
I'm not happy anymore
Not even when you make love to me
Do whatever you want with me
It's never stopped you before
You disappoint me
You had no hopes or expectations of me to start with
I was nothing
What can I do now?
What mother?
Where have you disappeared to, Oscar?
But what can I even talk to her about?
Could I talk about Ayanami with her?
All of my friends
Toji
Kensuke
All of their homes have been destroyed
And now they've left
Friends
I don't have anybody left
I could call my friend
I can't go see Ayanami again
I don't have courage to face her
I don't even know how to talk or act around her now
Asuka
Misato
Mother
What can I do?
The song is good
Singing brings joy and revitalizes the human soul
I think that song is the highest achievement of the Lilam culture
Don't you agree? Shinji Akari?
How do you know my name?
Everyone knows your name
I don't mean to sound rude but you're rather ignorant of your own position
Oh really? Who are you?
I am Kaoru
Kaoru Nagisa
I am like you
One of the selected children
The fifth child
You're the fifth child?
Um Mr. Nagisa
Call me Kaoru
Mr. Ikari
Mr. Ikari?
Oh no
You can call me Shinji
The fifth child has just arrived
Kaoru Nagisa
Kaoru of the seashore
And all of his past records have been erased
Just like Ray
But at least one record remains
He was born on the same day Second Impact occurred
The committee sent him directly to us
There must be something else
The Marduk reports file on the fifth child was classified
So I hacked into the intelligence department's computer system
I can't believe you did that
Oh it was worth doing
I found out where Ritsuko is
So what do you want to do about the fifth child's sync tests?
I don't have any tricks up my sleeve this time
Let's see what he can do
Take it down 0.3 more
Yes sir
Are these data readouts correct?
All of the test systems are operating correctly sir
Image I confirmed that there are no data errors
It's incredible that he can synchronize with unit 2
Even before we've reconfigured the core
He's amazing
But this isn't possible
Nevertheless it's happened
We must accept that fact and start an investigation into why it is so
You must be the first child am I correct?
You're Rei Ayanami
You are the same as I am
Identify yourself
The fifth child has made contact with Rei
I see
The magi are currently analyzing the nature of the fifth and what his powers may be
And we still don't know who or what he is
When the hell is this boy?
Shinji hasn't come back yet either
I guess I'm not deserving of his trust
Is trust
Central dogma is now over
Please use route
Me for the transfer
Hello
You weren't waiting here for me
Where are you?
No
Well not really waiting anyway
So what are you doing for the rest of the day?
Well
Usually when tests are over
I'll just take a shower and go home
But I don't really want to go home these days
The fact that you have a place where you could return home will lead you to happiness
That is a good fact
You think so?
I want to talk to you some more
May I come with you?
To the shower I mean
Aren't you going to go to the shower?
Yeah
Or do you mean no?
No I don't mean no
You are extremely afraid of any kind of initial contact aren't you
Are you that afraid of other people?
I know that by keeping others at a distance
You avoid a betrayal of your trust
But while you may not be hurt that way
You mustn't forget that you must endure the loneliness
Man can never completely erase this sadness
Because all men are fundamentally alone
It's time
Time to go?
Yeah
I have to go to bed
With me?
No
I think you have your own room
That they gave you I mean
Okay
You know pain is something that man must endure in his heart
And since the heart feels pain so easily some believe life is pain
You are delicate like glass
That is your heart is
It is?
Yes
This is worth earning my empathy
Empathy?
I'm saying I love you
Nerve
The nerve organization was established to execute the wishes of Zele
The wishes of Zele
It was intended to enact the scenario we had created
However
It appears to have become dominated by a single zealous individual
Yes it has
We must take it back into our own dominion
It is time
We must restore Nerve and the Ava series to their proper roles
Ikari
You will take responsibility for betraying Zele
I'm afraid there's not much time left for accomplishing our goal
However
The lance of Longinus which would have impeded the realization of our plan
Is now gone forever
The last angel shall soon appear
And with its destruction our wishes may be born soon Yui
Please have patience
Why am I here?
Why am I still alive?
For what purpose?
For whose purpose?
The fifth child?
In what way are he and I alike?
Thank God this apartment block is on the outskirts of town
It's a miracle that Aiden and you survived
And I can't guarantee your safety any longer
So the Haraki family will be taking care of you
From now on
I may not see you for a while Pen Pen
I think I should sleep on the floor
No
I'm staying at your place
I'm fine
I'll be okay on the floor
What did you want to say to me?
What?
You wanted to tell me something didn't you?
So much has happened since I came
Before this I lived with my teacher
It was calm and boring in those days
I wasn't really doing anything
But I was fine with that
There was really nothing that I had to do
Did you hate dealing with people?
More or less
But I didn't really care as much
However I really hated my father
Why am I telling all of this to Kaoru?
I think I may have been born just to meet you Shinji Ikari
Well did you get the data on him?
Yeah this is it
I sort of borrowed it from Lieutenant Ibuki without asking
I'm sorry that I made you do something like that
What is this?
Yeah it's no wonder that Maya can't talk about this
It's not even theoretically possible
Yeah it's getting more and more mysterious
How can he set his sync ratio at any level he chooses?
I guess it's time to go Maverick again
It's you again
How surprising
I have a question for you
Our conversation is being monitored you know
I don't care
The fifth child what is he?
He is probably the last angel
It is time let us go Adam's dark shadow
Servant of the Lilum
Ava unit 2 just activated
That's impossible
Where's Asuka?
She's in room 303 I've confirmed it
Who the hell is piloting it?
It's unmanned
The entry plug hasn't even been inserted into unit 2
Unmanned?
Then the fifth child isn't there
AT field detected in central dogma
Ava 2?
No the blood pattern is blue
It's definitely an angel
It's an angel?
That means that Ritz goes
The target has passed from the fourth defensive layer
And it's still descending
It's no good
We can't get the power to the linear carriage
Evacuate the area
Seal all shutters and bulkheads surrounding central dogma
We've got to buy ourselves some more time
Closing all bulkheads immediately
All personnel evacuate
God have mercy
Seal has sent an angel to us
The old man wants to advance his schedule using us as his tools
The last angel has intruded into the central dogma
It is now descending exactly as we planned
Dikare you were our good friend
Our comrade and understanding collaborator
However this shall be your final task
Now you must use unit 1
Unit 2
Unit 2 has penetrated the armored shutters
Surgut has penetrated the second barrier sir
Send unit 1 in to pursue it
Yes sir
Under all circumstances
The last angel must be kept from entering terminal dogma
But why did the angel take unit 2?
You don't think it's going to attempt to fuse with unit 2 do you?
Or will it try to bring about our total destruction?
No! No! No! No!
It's not possible!
I won't believe that Koro's an angel!
It's a lie!
It's a fact Shinji
You must accept it
Prepare for combat
Do you understand?
Shinji
You are late
Aving unit 1 descending via access route 2
It's about to make contact with the target
You betrayed me
You betrayed the trust I placed in you
You betrayed me just like my father did
You didn't want us to reach the fourth layer
It's about to confront the target
There he is
I have been waiting for you Shinji
Gauru
Asuka, I'm sorry
The Ava series was born from Adam
Born from man's antithesis
And yet the Lilum will utilize that which they hate most of all
In order to survive
I do not understand
Koro, stop!
Why is this happening?
Your Avas and I are composed of the same matter
Born from Adam, I can synchronize with it easily
As long as there is no dominant soul
And unit 2's soul is now hiding itself
Thus, Ava 2 is mine
No!
You've got your own ATV
Yes
At least that is what you Lilum call this thing
This is the light of my soul
A sacred territory
In which no one may intrude
Aren't you, Lilum, even aware yet
That your so-called AT field is merely that wall
That encloses every mind that exists
I don't understand what you're talking about!
Aah!
Both Avas have penetrated all the way down to the final layer
Twenty seconds until the target reaches terminal dock
If Unit 1's signals cut off or disappears
Worthany other change should occur for the worse
I know
I'll initiate the self-destruct for this entire facility
It's better than letting third impact take place
I'm sorry
It's alright
Dying beside you wouldn't be a bad way to go out
Thank you
This is mankind's fate
The thread of human hope is spun with the flax of sorrow
What the hell is that?
It's another AT field
Las strong as we've ever detected
It's shutting out everything
Light
Magnetism
Subatomic particles
It's blocking everything out?
I can't sense anything
The targets
Unit 2
Unit 1
They're all gone
We've lost communication with the pilot
Karu
Karu!
Don't do it,Karu!
No!Don't do it!
The door back!
Final safety says they're penetrating
They've reached it
Heaven's door has opened
Then the angel has finally reached its goal
Get ready
What's that?
What's going on?
It's another AT field
A field
A field as strong as the first one
It's appearing around terminal dogma
He's right
It's breaking through the other AT field
What is it?
Another angel?
I don't know
I can't confirm it
God!
It just disappeared
Disappeared?
The angel?
Adam
That from which we came
Must one who was born from Adam return to Adam?
Even though it will destroy man
Wait
This isn't
Lilith?
I see
I understand now
The Lilith
Lilith
I thank you Shinji
I wanted you to take unit 2 from me
Otherwise
With her
I might have survived much longer
Karu
But why?
It is my destiny to live forever
Though my survival
Will bring final destruction to the human race
However
It is possible for me to be killed
And whether I live or die
Makes no great difference
In truth
Dead may be the only absolute freedom there is
What are you?
Karu
I don't understand what you are talking about,Karu
This is my wish
Please destroy me
Destroy me
Otherwise you will be destroyed
Only one life form can be chosen to evade the destruction and seize the future
And you are not the existence which should die
You need the future
It is what you live for
Thank you Shinji
My life was meaningful
Because of you
Amen
Grace
king
Amen
ORGAN PLAYS
He was like me
And he was like Ayanami
I liked him too
Gauru should have survived
He was much better than I am
Not me
He deserved to live
No. The one who deserves to survive is the one who has the will to make it happen.
He wished for death. He ignored his will to survive and chose to die for a false hope.
Your survival is not a mistake, Shinji.
Misato, how can you be so cruel?
These days I taught to write a story.
I tried to make it happen, so I picked crad Wonka, Samsung, and Samsung.
Your tomb is Dabeiỡ, Isa, Mickey.
Throughthird
Thank you.
The last angel is gone, but Shinji's heart is filled with torment.
Misato and Asuka find their souls laid bare, seeking the help of others as they search for salvation.
Acceptance becomes a means to an end in the ending world.